<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>GDG DevFest Ukraine 2014</title>
    <description>October 24-25, Lviv, Ukraine. GDG DevFest - the biggest Google related event in Ukraine. 350+ attendees, 48 hours of pure Google content, 28+ speakers from Ukraine and beyond, 3 parallel tracks.</description>
    <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
      <item>
        <title>Conference networking tips</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive feature-image&quot; src=&quot;/2014/img/posts/conference_networking.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:none&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conference-networking-tips&quot;&gt;Conference networking tips&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My conference path began in 2001 when I spoke at my first student conference about utilization of one-way functions for building a perfect electronic money system. There I met a person acquaintance with whom helps and guides me to this day. After that, there were many events that happened in my life every half a year. Until in 2009, I plunged into this business. I have counted that over this time, I have attended, spoken at and organized around 100 conferences, meetings and meetups.
Sometimes, I encountered disappointment in some of my or others’ events. Several times, I have felt as the odd one out myself. But I can say that each time this happened, upon analysis, you could give one of the 10 tips I have decided to structure and make available to everyone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;The most precious part of a conference are the people who have gathered there.&lt;/strong&gt;
The talks are also valuable since they provide new information or inspire interesting ideas.
But the most valuable thing is the gathering of many experts and colleagues in your topic in a single place. The very format invites them to share thoughts, ideas and information. Sometimes at a conference, you can spend 15 minutes talking to people with quite a busy schedule, and it would normally take a long time to arrange a meeting with them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Investigate who will attend the conference a week or two in.&lt;/strong&gt;
Look through the schedule, find people who interest you, find them on Facebook or LinkedIn. Ask the organizers to forward your letter to. If it is possible, arrange everything with them before the.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;If you already know who interests you, find him and communicate BEFORE the.&lt;/strong&gt; If the person is truly interesting and popular, there will be a queue of those willing to talk to them after the. And you will have to make your way through the crowd for a 2-second contact. At the same time, I have repeatedly seen the same speaker calmly sit in the corner or walking the conference corridors alone just half an hour before that.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Sign business cards with information on what you have arranged with the.&lt;/strong&gt; I sometimes had around a hundred business cards after a good. These notes will help you recall what the conversation was. Or how you can be useful to each other.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Write follow-ups the day after the conference.&lt;/strong&gt; Several times, I have experimented and written follow-ups two or three weeks after the conference. This works, as well, if you were. But if you write follow-ups immediately after the conference, it will be much easier to continue the communication and fulfil agreements.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Have a good rest before the conference.&lt;/strong&gt; As a rule, stress on the body and brain rises drastically during the event – more information, more contacts, new. So you will need a lot of vigor and. It is better to arrive the day before and leave the pre-party before&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;People often ask what to do if you don’t know whom you need at the conference.&lt;/strong&gt; Do I need a certain kind of people? I have no clue where and how to find. The answer is simple: ask people you know to introduce you and in turn present them to those who interest. And you are extremely lucky if you know a professional networker, a person who has spent a long time inside the market and knows everything about everyone.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A conference is rather a place to get acquainted and outline the main collaboration milestones&lt;/strong&gt; than to carry out long negotiations and sign contracts. Although if you have met your key client who will give you more than all the others combined, take your chance.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be remembered for something.&lt;/strong&gt; It is very important to have your own specialty for which you will be remembered by everyone you talk. Oleksiy Mas appears at conferences in red shirts. Carpolan has been wearing long red T-shirts and baseball hat for as long as I can. These are exceptions but the more brightly comprehensible your style is, the better for you.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Be active.&lt;/strong&gt; And leave deep contemplation for the time when you’re returning home from the event. Though possibly you can combine the two.
And finally, the key point to sum – always remember your goals during the conference and shape them in advance. Be interested in others and tell about yourself.
If you use these tips, you will establish connections with a greater number of people and get more out of every conference you attend.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Originally published in &lt;a href=&quot;http://rchayka.com/conference-networking/&quot;&gt;Rostyslav Chayka blog&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2014 01:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/conference-networking-tips</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/conference-networking-tips</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet our Platinum Sponsor GlobalLogic</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globallogic.com.ua/en/&quot;&gt;GlobalLogic&lt;/a&gt; is a full-lifecycle product development services leader that combines deep domain expertise and cross-industry experience to connect makers with markets worldwide. The company is focused on software development in such domains as automotive, medicine, media and communications, retail and e-commerce, finance and business technology. Both ambitious startups and industry leaders are among GlobalLogic’s clients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The headquarters of GlobalLogic is located in the US, while it’s engineering and design centers are situated in eight countries of the world. More than 8000 specialists work with GlobalLogic, delivering about 1500 projects per year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globallogic.com.ua/&quot;&gt;GlobalLogic Ukraine&lt;/a&gt; is one of the TOP-5 largest IT companies of the country. Its offices are located in Kyiv, Kharkiv, Lviv and Mykolaiv, and more than 2400 IT experts are involved in GlobalLogic Ukraine’s projects. The company constantly welcomes talented professionals to join its team!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2014/img/posts/globallogic_main.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;GlobalLogic Ukraine organizes a wide variety of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globallogic.com.ua/en/news/&quot;&gt;expert events&lt;/a&gt;, such as TechTalks, hackathons, expert discussions etc. and supports the largest Ukrainian IT events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Learn more about the company and follow our updates!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;● &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globallogic.com.ua/en&quot;&gt;Official website&lt;/a&gt;
● &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/GlobalLogicUkraine&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;
● &lt;a href=&quot;http://vk.com/globallogicukraine&quot;&gt;VK&lt;/a&gt;
● &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/globallogic_ua&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;
● &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.globallogic.com.ua/en/news/&quot;&gt;YouTube&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 21 Oct 2014 17:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/platinum-sponsor-globallogic</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/platinum-sponsor-globallogic</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet our Platinum Sponsor DataArt</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;DataArt is a custom software development firm that builds advanced solutions for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataart.com/industry/financial-software&quot;&gt;financial&lt;/a&gt; services, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataart.com/industry/medical-software-development&quot;&gt;healthcare&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataart.com/industry/online-travel-solutions&quot;&gt;hospitality&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dataart.com/industry/publishing-software&quot;&gt;media &amp;amp; entertainment&lt;/a&gt; industries. Combining domain knowledge with offshore cost advantages and resource flexibility, DataArt develops industry-defining applications, helping clients optimize time-to-market and minimize software development risks in mission-critical systems. With an unrivaled talent pool of highly skilled software engineers in New York, London, Russia and Ukraine, DataArt provides the technical skill, accountability and industry knowledge needed to deliver custom applications on time and on budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our delivery and client engagement process is based on three key principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Software is People’s Business&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The measure of success is not the check in the bank, but the end user’s adoption of the new system&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;By the People&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A strong, well-organized team is key. We are fluent in the most sophisticated project methodologies, but deeply believe that it all comes down to two teams – ours and client’s, respecting and bringing the best in each other. We do not believe in people-independent delivery processes. Instead, we create an environment where people are motivated to stay and perform&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Humble, long term-focused vendor is worth two greedy ones&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We invest in relationships with our clients, by putting our own resources upfront to explore the new systems, fine-tune client-specific processes and mitigate risks&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We Make it Easy to Engage and Change Course as Needed&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2014/img/posts/dataart_img.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;we-bleed-agile&quot;&gt;We Bleed Agile!&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Business Level Approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We consider a project to be successful only when business stakeholders see the value of the investments required to complete the development. To ensure that the business needs are properly addressed we always align the project goals and timelines with the business goals&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Execution Level Approach&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We see the strength of DataArt’s service in our ability for efficient problem solving rather than working under the tight control of day-by-day supervision by the customer. This means that the engagement structure should include not only the development services but also such components as discovery, solution proof of concept, ongoing support and improvements&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Continuous Delivery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Continuous Delivery approach is at the heart of DataArt’s Delivery Model, providing a flexible but reliable framework for project execution and delivery. The key feature of the approach is an optimized delivery cycle so that changes can be implemented quickly and the results can become reliable and predictable
Roughly, 60% of projects employ the method at present and the number is growing. DataArt coaches, Delivery Managers and Senior PMs attend Agile-focused events, such as the annual Agilee Eastern Europe.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From Idea to Implementation in 8 Steps with DataArt&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/2014/img/posts/dataart_img2.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;1. Enquiry&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You send us your idea in any shape and form and we contact you in the next 24-hours for a quick interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;2. Estimate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We analyze collected information and come back to you with initial ballpark estimate and engagement plan. This may take several days, during which we stay in close contact with you to discuss new ideas, clarify requirements and inform you about our progress. Our goal here is to give you enough information to assess feasibility of the project as quickly as possible.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;3. Discovery&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Having engagement plan agreed and approved we start discovery phase during which we study your project requirements, environment and processes in-depth. This will result in a 360-view of the future project that includes functional requirements, architectural solution, development roadmap, project staffing, infrastructure, duration and costs, communication plan and project governance model. In many cases we prefer discovery phase to start with a series of face-to-face meetings to maximize efficiency of communications and establish personal contact. For that, our key project personnel will come to your premises or we’ll be equally happy to see you in one of our offices. Depending on size of the project this phase may take from 1 to 6 weeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;4. Contract&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We send you development contract and begin assembling project team. We understand that contract negotiation can take a while and in many cases we start setting up project infrastructure long before paperwork is actually completed to keep the momentum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;5. Production&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is where all technical work takes place. We believe that open communication is the key to success of any project, regardless of its size, methodology or technology chosen. We’ll do everything to build and maintain that “one goal, one team” culture in the project team and we expect the same from you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;6. Launch&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We’ll be there for you when you launch your product whether it is consumer-oriented or enterprise solution. We’ll be glad to help you choose hosting platform and develop safe deployment procedures. We’ll even take a night shift on launch day to ensure smooth start of your product or perform deployment over weekend to minimize impact on your business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;7. Support&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even simplest software projects require maintenance and support. We understand that and we are always ready to provide post-production support if necessary in addition to our standard warranty period.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;8. Hand-over&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the time comes for us to step aside, we will provide all necessary resources to perform smooth and seamless handover of the project to your team. We’ll help your staff to get up to speed with project deliverables and infrastructure and we’ll always stay just one phone call away to answer your questions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DataArt has been consistently named one of the top or fastest growing IT outsourcing providers worldwide by BusinessWeek, CMP’s Global Sourcing 100, International Association of Outsourcing Professionals and Inc. 5000. DataArt clients include Standard &amp;amp; Poor’s, Harmonic Fund Services, Ogilvy, artnet, Panasonic, Cancer Research, Charles River Laboratories, Betfair, Misys, leading asset management firms and three of the world’s top ten investment banks.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 16 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/platinum-sponsor-dataart</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/platinum-sponsor-dataart</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet our Diamond Sponsor SoftServe</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;SoftServe — is Ukraine’s largest IT company that provides services in the development, testing and maintenance of information systems and business solutions.
Since the establishment of the company, more than 150 companies from all over the world have become our clients, among which famous brands from the US, Canada, Western Europe.
Since 1993, SoftServe has accomplished more than 3500 projects for over 100 leading companies all over the world. 3450 professionals from various fields of IT work at SoftServe.
Today we have representative offices and development centers in 19 major cities of 8 countries.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 15 Oct 2014 23:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/diamond-sponsor-softserve</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/diamond-sponsor-softserve</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Meet our Hackathon Sponsor Lohika</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img class=&quot;img-responsive feature-image&quot; src=&quot;/2014/img/posts/lohika_banner.jpg&quot; style=&quot;display:none&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lohika provides high-quality services of software development for the world’s largest technology companies, as well as those, who are looking for custom innovative solutions in IT. Our Head office is located in San Bruno, California, in the heart of Silicon Valley.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our 650 strong engineering teams specialize in current and emerging technology needs such as web &amp;amp; enterprise applications, cloud technology, mobile applications, and quality assurance from our engineering teams based Kyiv, Lviv, and Odessa, Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We always ready to support professional IT communities which encourage people to share their knowledge and make an impact into development of Ukrainian IT sector and we are also enjoy driving several IT communities in Lviv and Odessa. Our last initiative is &lt;a href=&quot;http://morning.lohika.com/&quot;&gt;Morning@Lohika&lt;/a&gt; in Lviv Office - is a platform for different technology meetups that has a mission to shake-up IT community and supply it with high quality sessions from professionals from all over Ukraine. You will have a chance to visit &lt;strong&gt;Morning@Lohika on the 15th of November&lt;/strong&gt;, and listen to  Mikalai Alimenkou - our welcomed guest from Kyiv, Java Tech Lead and Scrum Master with the topic &lt;strong&gt;“Continuous Delivery”&lt;/strong&gt;. You can follow updates at event &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/groups/morning.lohika/&quot;&gt;Facebook page&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And don’t forget to visit &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.facebook.com/pages/Lohika/253302288033498&quot;&gt;Lohika at Facebook&lt;/a&gt; we always have something interesting to share :)&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/meet-hackathon-sponsor-lohika</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/meet-hackathon-sponsor-lohika</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diamond Sponsor: ELEKS - striving for excellence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/img/posts/eleks_infographics_1000.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;ELEKS - striving for excellence&quot; style=&quot;width: 100%;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From morning alarm clocks on our mobiles to evening movie sessions on our PCs – this is how  far technology has spread into our lives. Tons of gadgets, apps and other software have become our trivia. Not only we use them - we make them. 
In this vast and rapidly changing industry of IT, how can you find a company that differs? Someone that stands out, a company that sets the pace and is an industry leader. ELEKS Software, headquartered in Lviv, Ukraine, is that kind of the company. Years of experience, impressive projects ranging from healthcare to motion picture production and with almost a thousand employees witness better than any words. ELEKS really has something more to offer. Both top managers and programmers testify that this success has been built on several basic principles:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;people-who-use-technology-people-who-create-it&quot;&gt;People, who use technology, people who create it&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Computers, tablets, mobile devices and tons of other gadgets  - all these years we’ve so gotten used to the fact that popular applications and programs have no face; we’ve forgotten that they were created by normal people, with their own strong and weak points, habits and hobbies. Do not hide the human face behind the technology – is the first rule ELEKS obeys. Furthermore, company reps believe that it is their people who make all the difference and provide excellent results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, ELEKS pays special attention not only to their employees, but their clients as well. The technology has to work for the ones it’s being created for: be it NASA astronauts or insurance officers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;big-company--vast-possibilities&quot;&gt;Big company – vast possibilities&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the exact numbers are not certain, it is safe to speculate that there are thousands of companies in Ukraine today that create technology on the outsource principle. Big and small, proficient in one or multiple fields – there are loads of them, but only few can be recognized as true professionals. ELEKS has more than 20 years of experience, dozens of successfully released projects and about a thousand employees all over Ukraine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s admit: one day you might wake up thinking you want to change something about your work. At ELEKS this doesn’t mean changing your workplace, you can easily pursue your ambitions here with “a little help of your friends” (that’s from The Beatles). Company provides a number of courses to enhance your qualifications, language training, various master-classes for staff, not to mention the constant knowledge exchange between peers and coworkers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;innovations-or-what-is-trendsetting-at-it&quot;&gt;Innovations or what is trendsetting at IT&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One more crucial aspect in IT business is time. Not only do you have to follow the news, you have to foresee change, being Nostradamus and Galileo in one person. One of the busiest departments at ELEKS is the R&amp;amp;D division, where specialists learn what’s hot today and try to imagine what could be trendy in the next season. Just like fashion, only in technology.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;higher-faster-stronger&quot;&gt;Higher, faster, stronger!&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Today any work can be easily compared to sports. That is why, inspired by the Olympic motto, ELEKS encourages their employees to be proactive. Every programmer, Q&amp;amp;A or project manager knows that his/her effort is one more brick into company’s reputation and good market position. Being effective is already a motivation.


#### Meeting standards in not enough, there is a strong need for creating new ones

HR-masters have learned a while ago that salary stopped being the strongest motivation for an employee. An environment filled with professionals, good working conditions and being proud of your job have become factors of new importance, especially in today’s workforce. Being successful in Ukraine today means fighting the obstacles rather than enjoying the benefits. ELEKS itself shows an example of the outstanding company built according to the civilized standards here, in Ukraine. Despite all, they can engage the brightest specialists, high-quality resources, meet deadlines and bring up the best solutions. So aren’t all those things one can be proud of?

Inspired by technology, driven by value, people at ELEKS still manage to stay patriotic. “Rewarding company performance is not just about our personal profit. We are proud to create the new face of our region and Ukraine as well”, - they say.

Break the stereotypes and instead create new innovative work schemes - that&#39;s what people do at ELEKS. Especially, if they’re based on basics principles: being respectful to people and laws, being responsible to yourself and your peers, and finally, to always have a desire to work on and improve yourself, your country and your environment.

&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 19 Sep 2014 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/diamond-sponsor-eleks</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/diamond-sponsor-eleks</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Call for Papers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;GDG DevFest Ukraine 2014 will be held 24-25th of October in ancient city of Lviv. If you want to be part of this great event as a speaker you knocked at the good door.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;presenters--who-should-speak-at-the-devfest-conference&quot;&gt;Presenters – who should speak at the DevFest Conference?&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;developers (freelance and hired)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;companies developing software (apps, tools, frameworks etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;research institutions with Google relevant activities&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;companies, organisations and individuals using Google technologies&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you belong to one of those groups you are cordially invited to submit a talk proposal (or a number of proposals). An independent program committee assesses the proposals and selects the actual conference talks.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;themes-and-topics--what-do-we-expect&quot;&gt;Themes and topics – what do we expect?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Our team prepared set of interesting topics in but if you have any cool idea you want to share not from this list, feel free to submit it as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;android&quot;&gt;Android&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google I/O 2014&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Material Design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Migration to ART&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Android Camera API&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;New Job Scheduler&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Storage Access Framework&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Elevation &amp;amp; Clipping&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;General&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android Continuous Integration&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Loaders, Cursor Adapters&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Android Animations&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Patterns in Android development&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;web&quot;&gt;Web&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;AngularJS (1x and 2.0)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Dart (AngularDart, server-side)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Polymer and WebComponents&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Material Design in Web&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ChromeOS (apps development)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Web Performance (tools, techniques, approaches)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h5 id=&quot;cloud&quot;&gt;Cloud&lt;/h5&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Google Cloud Platform
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Compute Engine&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;App Engine&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Storages (SQL, NoSQL, BigData)&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;APIs&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Go (as a language for a Cloud Ready Apps)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;please-submit-your-proposals-herehttpbitlydfua-c4p&quot;&gt;Please submit your proposals &lt;a href=&quot;http://bit.ly/dfua-c4p&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Deadline&lt;/strong&gt; is September 1, 2014&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Please note:&lt;/strong&gt; There is no guarantee that a submission will be put onto the conference agenda!&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program committee picks the most interesting talk proposals and informs the selected submitters until September 15, 2014.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;any-questions&quot;&gt;Any questions?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Email organizers at &lt;a href=&quot;&amp;#109;&amp;#097;&amp;#105;&amp;#108;&amp;#116;&amp;#111;:&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#118;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#100;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&quot;&gt;&amp;#100;&amp;#101;&amp;#118;&amp;#102;&amp;#101;&amp;#115;&amp;#116;&amp;#064;&amp;#103;&amp;#100;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#111;&amp;#114;&amp;#103;&amp;#046;&amp;#117;&amp;#097;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 12:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/call-for-papers</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/call-for-papers</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hello World!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;We’re very excited - not just because of the inordinate amount of caffeine based products consumed - 
but also because our team are putting together 
the final missing parts to the biggest Google related event in Ukraine - &lt;a href=&quot;http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/&quot;&gt;GDG DevFest 2014&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year event will take place in cultural capital of Ukraine - Lviv. Being a unique European city in Ukraine, Lviv is among top 10 cities of the world to visit in 2014 according to the travel group “The Rough Guide” and is among top 10 cities for spending weekends in Europe according to Lonely Planet. So take your time to spend weekend in last hidden gem in the Europe in company of experts and technical geeks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So should you also be excited? Well yes… and here’s why!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Attendance&lt;/strong&gt;: we’re expecting over 350 attendees&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Topic&lt;/strong&gt;: more than 48 hours of pure Google technologies&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Date&lt;/strong&gt;: 24-25 of October, expect hackathon and workshops on a first day and conference on the second&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Venue&lt;/strong&gt;: Kinopalace Cinema - for a first time we’ll make technical event in real cinema directly in the heart of the ancient city of Lviv&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Speakers&lt;/strong&gt;: we’re in the process of finalizing the list of speakers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;but we’ve already secured a first batch of experts:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dawid Ostrowski&lt;/strong&gt; - Developer Relation from Google, who excited about cloud technologies&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Mateusz Herych&lt;/strong&gt; - Android GDE and GDG organizer from Krakow&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Dmytro Danylyk&lt;/strong&gt; - developer, blogger, speaker, author of open source 1000+ star libraries &lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Roman Mazur&lt;/strong&gt; - speaker on various international conferences like Droidcon Eastern Europe and Ankara Developer Days&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More details about speakers, DevFest Hackathon and Lviv will appear in subsequent posts, meantime like us on &lt;a href=&quot;https://facebook.com/GDGLviv&quot;&gt;Facebook&lt;/a&gt;, follow on &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/intent/user?screen_name=GDGLviv&quot;&gt;Twitter&lt;/a&gt;, add to circles in &lt;a href=&quot;https://plus.google.com/b/102444623953913144164&quot;&gt;Google+&lt;/a&gt; or subscribe to our &lt;a href=&quot;http://gdg.us5.list-manage1.com/subscribe/post?u=9fc8aa205b0521b5f05fc8e1e&amp;amp;id=ae0fb459fc&quot;&gt;mailing list&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/feed.xml&quot;&gt;RSS feed&lt;/a&gt; in order not to miss any cool stuff about festival.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 11:00:00 +0300</pubDate>
        <link>http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/hello-world</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://devfest.gdg.org.ua/2014/blog/hello-world</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
